Finding Aid for Ste. Anne’s Church (Detroit, Mich.) registers, 1704-1842
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ste. Anne’s Church (Detroit, Mich.) registers 1704-1842
Ste. Anne’s Church (Detroit, Mich.).
3 microfilm reels
86966 mf 534c, mf535c, mf 536c
Church registers, baptismal records, and death and marriage records dating from 1704 to 1842.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were made available for microfilming by the Archdiocese of Detroit (donor no. 2888 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
Researcher must complete separate registration form before access to this record group will be permitted.
On July 26, 1701, two days after his arrival, Antoine de la Mothe Cadillac, founder of Detroit, built a chapel dedicated to Ste. Anne, patron saint of New France. Fire swept through the settlement on October 5, 1703 destroying the church, rectory, and several other buildings. The parish's earliest records were consumed in that fire. Subsequent records, dating from 1704, are now the second oldest continuous Roman Catholic parish records in the nation. These records of Ste Anne's Church are in the custody of the Archives of the Archdiocese of Detroit.
The record group includes church registers, baptismal records, and death and marriage records dating from 1704 to 1842.
Subjects:
Catholic Church--Michigan--Detroit.; St. Anne's Church (Detroit, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); French Americans--Michigan.; Registers of births, etc.
- Ste. Anne's church registers
  - Registre de Ste. Anne, Detroit, 1704-1801
    - 1704-1744 (Reel 1)
    - 1744-1780 (Reel 1)
    - 1780-1801 (Reel 2)
  - Baptismal records, 1801-1848
    - 1801-1810 (Reel 2)
    - 1810-1848 (Reel 2)
  - Death records, 1801-1842 (Reel 3)
  - Marriage records, 1801-1842 (Reel 3)
  - Chapelle du nordest-Baptisms, marriages, burials, 1810-1838 (Reel 3)
- Most Holy Trinity Church, Detroit
  - Marriages and deaths, 1834-1848 (Reel 3)
  - Baptisms, 1835-1869 (Reel 3)